District of Columbia Public Library 040
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
- Series 9: Project Files, ca. 1960s
  - Pub Reinforced Binding, 1966 (Box Shelved, Folder 23)
  - D.C. Reorganization Model Cities, Undated (Box Shelved, Folder 24)
  - Policies and Procedures, Undated (Box Shelved, Folder 25)
- Series 10: Scrapbooks, 1896-1956
  Series contains 49 scrapbooks containing photographs, memorabilia, program flyers, booklets, clippings, letters, and other documents about events and activities of the library, generally annually. Also contains Clara Herbert and George Bowerman scrapbooks.
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 157, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 158, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 159, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 162, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 162, Folder 2)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 163, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 164, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 165, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 167, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 168, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 169, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 170, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 171, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 172, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 173, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 174, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 175, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 176, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 177, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 178, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 179, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 181, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 182, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 184, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 185, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 186, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 187, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 188, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 191, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 192, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 193, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 195, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 196, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 197, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 198, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 199, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 200, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 201, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 202, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 203, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 204, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - Annual or biennial scrapbooks, 1896-1956 (Box 206, Folder 1)
  - Clara Herbert and George Bowerman scrapbooks, Undated (Box 207, Folder 1)
  - Clara Herbert and George Bowerman scrapbooks, Undated (Box 208, Folder 1)
- Series 12: Procedural Orders, 1967-1972
  Contains orders recommended by DCPL staff and passed by the Board arranged in sequential number of procedures followed by the DC Public Library system.
  - 4 Binders, Undated (Box Shelf, Folder 1)
- Series 13: Administrative Orders, 1948-1970
  Contains orders recommended by DCPL staff and passed by the Board arranged in sequential number of administrative functions of the DC Public Library system.
  - Administrative Orders and background files, 1948-1970 (Box 209, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Orders and background files, 1948-1970 (Box 210, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Orders and background files, 1948-1970 (Box 211, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Orders and background files, 1948-1970 (Box 212, Folder 1)
  - 1 binder, Undated (Box Shelf, Folder 1)
- Series 14: Questionnaires, 1947-1972
  Contains 10 three-ring notebooks of questionnaires and responses by patrons about the services of the library.
  - 10 three-ring notebooks, 1947-1972 (Box Shelf, Folder 1)
- Series 15: Washingtoniana Division Records, 1920-2005
  This series contains official files and records of the activities, programs, policies, and staff of the Washingtoniana Division of DCPL, established as an official division in 1926. The records include daybooks, records of gifts, clippings about the division, a scrapbook, program publicity flyers, book lists, and operational records. Series also contains brochures, flyers, posters and some records from planning of the annual DC Historical Studies conference jointly sponsored by the Washingtoniana, the Historical Society of Washington DC, and the George Washington University from 1972 to current. Videotapes and audiotapes of the conference are in the AV Series.
  - Day books, 1933-1956 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Day books, 1933-1956 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Record of Gifts, Undated (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Records, 1928-1971 (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Administrative records, 1987-2004 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Administrative records, 1987-2004 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Division History, 1980 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Division History, 1980 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - GRF Key documents, Undated (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - GRF Key documents, Undated (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1905-1945 (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Program flyers, 1995 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Historical Studies conference brochures/flyers/records, 1978-2005 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Historical Studies conference brochures/flyers/records, 1978-2005 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Historical Studies conference brochures/flyers/records, 1978-2005 (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - Historical Studies conference brochures/flyers/records, 1978-2005 (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - Historical Studies conference brochures/flyers/records, 1978-2005 (Box 143, Folder 1)
  - Oral History Research Center records and Dr. Greenlee's files, 1980s (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Oral History Research Center records and Dr. Greenlee's files, 1980s (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Oral History Research Center records and Dr. Greenlee's files, 1980s (Box 128, Folder 1)
- Series 17: Publications, 1997-current
  This series contains publications primarily prepared by the Marketing Department, formerly Library Services and Program Office, of DCPL, including program posters and flyers, staff manuals, staff bulletins, flyers, and the monthly calendar (currently Beyond Words).
  - Flyers, posters, and other DCPL publications, Undated (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Flyers, posters, and other DCPL publications, Undated (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - Flyers, posters, and other DCPL publications, Undated (Box 140, Folder 1)
  - Your Library Bulletin, Undated (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - Marketing publications, Undated (Box 141, Folder 1)
  - Beyond Words, Undated (Box 142, Folder 1)
- Series 18: Maps and Architectural Drawings, 1903-2003
  This series contains blueprints, architectural drawings and renderings of the Carnegie Library, the MLK Library and most branches. It also contains rendering for a proposed renovation of MLK in 2003.
  - Maps with Library building locations, Undated (Box Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Central Library - Mt. Vernon Square, 1900-1936 (Box Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Downtown Central Library - 901 G Street, 1965-1966 (Box Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - Downtown Central Library - 901 G Street, 1965-1966 (Box Drawer 4, Folder 1)
  - Advertisement for Central Library and MLK, Undated (Box Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - Drawing of opening ceremony for Carnegie Library, 1903 (Box Drawer 5, Folder 2)
  - Drawings for proposed renovation of MLK, 2003 (Box Drawer 6, Folder 1)
  - Branch and MLK Library blueprints, Undated (Box Drawer 7, Folder 1)
  - Branch and MLK Library blueprints, Undated (Box Drawer 8, Folder 1)
  - Branch and MLK Library blueprints, Undated (Box Drawer 9, Folder 1)
  - Branch and MLK Library blueprints, Undated (Box Drawer 10, Folder 1)